# ABHISHEK ALFRED SINGH

#### • DETAILS •

Edmonton, Alberta
Canada
+1-825-440-9866
alfred.abhishek@gmail.com

• LINKS •

Github

<u>LinkedIn</u>

° SKILLS °

Java

**GRPC** 

Golang

Python

SQL (PostGreSQL)

C++

Docker

Git

Linux

**Distributed Systems** 

Database systems

**Blockchains** 

#### PROFILE

I am a Backend Systems Engineer with experience in building high performance microservices and secure transaction processing systems for data and network management systems. I have been building decentralized data management systems in Java, Golang, Python and C++ since 2018. In addition to that I have more than five years of experience building high performance middleware systems, and webservices at Nokia (2013-2018). I'm a Permanent Resident of Canada and live in Edmonton, Alberta. I'm looking for opportunities as a Software Engineer.

#### EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

#### Software Engineer at Alvita Enterprises Inc., Edmonton, Canada

September 2022 — Present

I work on building Alvita Enterprises's digital marketing platform. I also work as a Software Consultant working on Web development projects. As part of my work I have used Python, Flask, Golang, Docker, PostGreSQL (SQL), RocksDB, Apache Kafka, JavaScript, NodeJS, Core Java with SpringBoot, and AWS.

# Research Assistant (Remote) at University of California, Santa Cruz and Irvine September 2018 — January 2023

My work involves building research prototypes for decentralized data management systems. I work at the UCI EdgeLab with Prof. Faisal Nawab from the Information Systems Group at UC, Irvine, California. The following is the list of projects I've completed at UCI EdgeLab.

- TransEdge [<u>To be published in Proceedings 26th International Conference on Extending Database Technology, (EDBT 2023)</u>]- fast read-only transaction processing system for a Byzantine fault-tolerant system. Languages and frameworks used: Java, Python, Git, Bash, AWS, RocksDB, Apache Kafka, Git
- WedgeBlock [To be published in Proceedings 26th International Conference on <u>Extending Database Technology, (EDBT 2023)</u>] - fast and secure offchain logging framework for Blockchain systems providing untrusted offchain applications: Languages and frameworks: Python, Solidity, Ethereum Blockchain, Git
- 3. Clen secure transaction processing system for a hybrid decentralized system. Languages and frameworks: Golang, Java, Bash, Docker, Python, Flask, Git

## Software Engineer at Nokia, Bangalore, India

July 2013 — August 2018

Worked on designing and building high performance middleware for Nokia's network management system. Languages, frameworks and protocols used: Java, Python, Bash, Docker, Corba, SNMP, XML, SOAP, SpringBoot, J2EE, SFTP, SCP, SSL, Agile, Cross platform systems design

#### EDUCATION

M.S. Computer Science, University of California, Santa Cruz, California October 2018 — December 2020

M.E. Information Technology, Bangalore University, Bangalore

October 2011 — June 2013

Graduated with Distinction

### **INTERNSHIPS**

# Intern Member of Technical Staff - Blockchain Engineering at VMware Inc, Palo Alto,

June 2022 — September 2022

I worked with VMware's permissioned blockchain team. My responsibilities were to build a new testing interface for their open source blockchain library called Concord-bft. Languages and Frameworks used: Python, GRPC, Docker, C++, Cmake

Software Engineering Intern at Alcatel-Lucent (Nokia), Bangalore, India July 2012 - June 2013

I worked on building prototype protocol conversion API for HNBAP/RANAP to SIP in C++ for Alcatel-Lucent Femtocells. Langauges and frameworks used: Perl, Python, Bash, C++, Make

#### **★** PUBLICATIONS

#### TransEdge: Supporting Efficient Read Queries Across Untrusted Edge Nodes

To appear in Proceedings. 26th International Conference on Extending Database Technology (EDBT 2023), Ioánnina, Greece, March 28-31, 2023

## WedgeBlock: An Off-Chain Secure Logging Platform for Blockchain Applications

To appear in Proceedings. 26th International Conference on Extending Database Technology (EDBT 2023), Ioánnina, Greece, March 28-31, 2023

PeloPartition: Improving Blockchain Resilience to Network Partitioning

Published in 2022 IEEE Conference on Blockchain (Blockchain)

You've got a Friend in ME (Mobile Edge): Blockchain Processing with Cloud Node Backup

Published in 2022 IEEE Conference on Blockchain (Blockchain)

Analyzing Soft and Hard Partitions of Global-Scale Blockchain Systems

Published in 2022 IEEE Conference on Blockchain (Blockchain)

LiftChain: A Scalable Multi-Stage NFT Transaction Protocol

Published in 2022 IEEE Conference on Blockchain (Blockchain)

WedgeDB: Transaction Processing for Edge Databases, , Santa Cruz, California

Poster published in the Proceedings of the ACM Symposium on Cloud Computing, 2019

Additional Publications

Publications in IEEE Conferences - https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/author/38557615200